<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Coding Journal</title>
    <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Coding Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 09:29:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.kulman.sk/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Hockey App to distribute Windows Phone apps</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/using-hockey-app-to-distribute-windows-phone-apps</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 09:29:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/using-hockey-app-to-distribute-windows-phone-apps</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Distributing Windows Phone apps to testers has always been a pain. The Private Beta in the Windows Store intended for this is not very flexible and it got much worse with Windows 10 (generating promotional code that can take up to 24 hours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the better ways to solve the beta build distribution is using a service like &lt;a href=&#34;http://hockeyapp.net/&#34;&gt;Hockey App&lt;/a&gt;, that Microsoft recently acquired. To be able to use Hockey App (or any other service) you need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://products.websecurity.symantec.com/orders/enrollment/microsoftCert.do&#34;&gt;buy a $299 certificate from Symantec&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You then use the certificate to sign the XAP or APPX files of your app. Those signed binaries can be than installed on devices with the correct application enrollment token directly from Hockey App, bypassing the Windows Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my clients got persuaded to try this approach after some problem with the Windows Store Private Beta and bough the certificate. It took a week for the purchase to go through and another week to finally get the certificate in the correct PFX format from Symantec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adding password to the PFX certificate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PFX certificate file I got had an empty password. This is quite a problem for all the Microsoft tools that work with certificates, especially for XapSignTool. I could not make the tools work with an empty password so I had to change the password first. This is done quite easily using using OpenSSL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/24cb76710fc7d6c9f2cb.js?file=pwd.bat&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generating application enrollment token&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To allow the devices to install the signed XAP (or APPX) you need to generate an application enrollment token that will be installed on the devices. The process is quite simple, just call&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/24cb76710fc7d6c9f2cb.js?file=aet.bat&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as a result you will get three files: AET.aet, AET.aetx, AET.xml. Get the AET.aetx file and upload it to Hockey App by clicking Add version and drag and dropping the file to the upload dialog. The company profile for your app in Hockey App will get updated using this file. This is done only once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Signing the binary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time you submit a new build to Hockey App, you need to sign the binary (XAP in my case) with the certificate. The [signing process differs for XAP and APPX files][1].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For XAP files it is just calling the right PowerShell script with the correct parameters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/24cb76710fc7d6c9f2cb.js?file=sign.bat&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the result is .. an error &lt;code&gt;Signtool Error: This file format cannot be signed because it is not recognized&lt;/code&gt;. So I had to do some research. I found a &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/20970686/error-signing-windows-phone-xap-file-signtool-error-this-file-format-cannot&#34;&gt;developer describing the same problem on StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;. The solution was to install &lt;a href=&#34;http://downloads.tomsguide.com/silverlight-microsoft,0301-10659.html&#34;&gt;Silverlight 5.1.30514.0&lt;/a&gt;. This was really strange, it is a Silverlight runtime not an SDK and it does not get installed with Visual Studio or the Windows Phone SDK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributing the app&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you upload a signed binary to Hockey App, your testers can download it using a web browser to their devices. Each device needs to install the company profile (the application enrollment token) once, and then can install the builds you provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation of the Windows Phone app builds is a bit strange, no install progress or success messages, the app just appears in the list ofter one or two minutes. But it works, and it is much faster and more flexible than the Private Beta provides by the Windows Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[1]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/apps/dn168929(v=vs.105).aspx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to handle localization strings provided by the client in a Windows Phone app</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/how-to-handle-localization-strings-provided-by-client</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 09:29:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/how-to-handle-localization-strings-provided-by-client</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I currently work on a Windows Phone 8.1 app for a client with an interesting approach to app localization. They have a Google Docs sheet with all the localization string for the app in all the supported languages and a tool that converts this localization strings in to per-language versioned JSON files. The generated JSON files are kept in a git repository. The Android, iOS and now my Windows Phone app should have the git repository added as a submodule. When a new version of the JSON files with the localization appear in the submodule, the app should use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deciding the localization approach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the old days of Windows Phone 7 and Windows Phone 8 I would simply write an utility that reads the newest version of the JSON localization files and generate a RESX file for each language. RESX is XML format that is simple to generate. If you had a localized string with a key say Game, you would put it everywhere when the localization of the word game was needed. Simple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Windows Phone 8.1 (and 10) you should use RESW files for localization. This is the new x:Uid approach that, in my honest opinion, really sucks. It forces you to duplicate string if you use I string in multiple places, there is no design time support, you never know what UI element are localized and what you forgot to localize. Simply put, it is a mess. This approach is not usable at all with the string client provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no way to make any script generate a RESW file with duplicated string matching the multiple usages of each string. If you have a localized string with a key Game and 2 TextBlocks and 1 Buttons that use it, you need to put it into the RESW file 3 times, once for each UI element. SO instead of a Game key, you would have a GameTextBlock.Text key, an AnotherGameTextBlock.Text and a GameButton.Content key, all with the same value and applied in design time. Madness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using RESX files on Windows Phone 8.1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One approach to solve this problem is to use the good old RESX files with your Windows Phone 8.1 project. Typically by creating a Portable Class Library (PCL) with the RESX files, doing a bit of configuration for the supported languages and linking this PCL project to your Windows Phone 8.1 project. You can find a few articles about this approach online and also a few gotchas and their solutions. It sounds like a good idea at first, but it is too problematic for my tastes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried this approach but ended frustrated with too many problems too solve, like Visual Studio hanging when deploying to a device when using RESX files. So I decided to go with a custom solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generating Windows Phone 8-like localization strings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I decided to generate a class that would look and behave similar to the old Windows Phone 8-like localization strings class. The idea is quite simple, no need to a PCL or any RESX files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to create a directory and empty RESW files for each supported language in the Windows Phone 8.1 project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/languages.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then write a script that generates all the RESW files from the newest JSON localization files&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/53a29b6e2143cac1ec8a.js?file=localization-converter-1.cs&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now with the RESW files populated with all the localization string it is time to put them to use. First I created a &lt;code&gt;LocalizedStrings&lt;/code&gt; class very similar to the one in Windows Phone 8:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/53a29b6e2143cac1ec8a.js?file=LocalizedStrings.cs&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and added it to &lt;code&gt;App.xaml&lt;/code&gt; as a dictionary resources called &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/53a29b6e2143cac1ec8a.js?file=App.xaml&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting ans still missing part is the &lt;code&gt;AppResources&lt;/code&gt; class referenced in &lt;code&gt;LocalizedStrings&lt;/code&gt;. It is a partial class, consisting of &lt;code&gt;ResourceLoader&lt;/code&gt; instance to get the string at runtime and a Singleton to get the string from C# code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/53a29b6e2143cac1ec8a.js?file=AppResources.cs&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part of this class is generated by the same script that generates the RESW files. For each key in the localization string, it generates a property like this in the &lt;code&gt;AppResources&lt;/code&gt; class&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/53a29b6e2143cac1ec8a.js?file=AppResources.strings.cs&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code to generate this is part of the script&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/53a29b6e2143cac1ec8a.js?file=localization-converter-2.cs&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The result&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you put all this pieces together, you have a RESW files with all the localization strings and a localization class that can be generated on demand. I run the script and generate the files every time there is an update in the git submodule with the JSON localization files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I want to use any of these localization string in XAML, I simply use it like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/53a29b6e2143cac1ec8a.js?file=xaml-usage.xaml&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a binding allows me to use to use the same localization keys for many elements and I do not have to duplicate the keys like in the x:Uid scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I need to used a localization string in C#, I have a strongly typed access to it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/igorkulman/53a29b6e2143cac1ec8a.js?file=csharp-usage.cs&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;instead of creating a &lt;code&gt;ResourceLoader&lt;/code&gt; instance and calling &lt;code&gt;GetString&lt;/code&gt; with a string parameter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another approach would be having a public property with the &lt;code&gt;AppResources&lt;/code&gt; instance in a &lt;code&gt;ViewModel&lt;/code&gt; base class, it would make the binding shorter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A week with Microsoft Band 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/a-week-with-microsoft-band-2</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 09:29:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/a-week-with-microsoft-band-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About a week ago I got a Microsoft Band 2. I really wanted to try out the device, because this second generation does not look as bad as the first one, there are new sensors added and generally it should be a visible improvement over the original Band. I have been an iPhone users for about two years now (approximately the time since last good Windows Phone device was released), currently using iPhone 6s so I was also curious to know how well the Band 2 works with iOS. This blog post sums up my impressions after a week of using the Microsoft Band 2 with my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expectations and habits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I have to state that I am not a notifications junkie. I do not like being interrupted all the time. On my phone, only phone calls and SMS ale allowed to notify me with a sound and stay in the notifications center. Other few selected apps like Outlook, Twitter, Messenger, Sunrise are allowed to use iOS badges on my phone, just to let me know that there is a Twitter message or something I may be interested in. Other than that, no notifications for me. I guess I am not a typical user when it comes to notifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have already guessed, I was interested in the Microsoft Band 2 primarily as a health device, not as a smartwatch or distractions device. My expectation and goal is to move and exercise more and sleep better, not to immediately know about every new Facebook post (I do not even have the Facebook app installed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look and feel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always thought the first Microsoft Band was big, bulky and did not look very good. The Band 2 is nicer, the area around the display is not as bulky, the main mass of the device was moved to the other side. This makes you wear the device with the display inside your wrist, &amp;ldquo;military style&amp;rdquo;, the opposite of how you usually wear a watch. Event the guy in a video ad I saw wore it this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wearing the band on the inside allows a nice feature, turning the watch face on when you flip your wrist. This can save you precious battery compared to having the watch faces always visible, until you realize you turn your wrist a lot during the day, for example while eating. The band is made of rubber and it scratches quite easily. The scratches are visible when you look at the band from up close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The device feels solid, I did not feel uncomfortable wearing. I though using the keyboard while wearing it maybe be a problem and it partially was. I could use the keyboard while using my desktop computer, but I had to be careful not to scratch the display on the edge when using my Thinkpad notebook. Using the Thinkpad while wearing the Band was not really comfortable, I had to position my hands differently that I am used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial setup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I installed the Microsoft Health app for iOS on my phone, the pairing was quick without any problems. The app installed a firmware updated to the Band 2 while pairing. The next day the Microsoft Health app was updated and it updated the firmware in the Band 2 again. This time  the firmware update brought two new functions: controlling the music playback and inactivity reminder. I do not much care about the music controls, I can pause my podcasts using the button on my headphones. Inactivity reminder is a great feature, reminding you to wake up and take a few steps when sitting idle for a long time. I really do not know why this function was not in the Band from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/BandSetup.png&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-width&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/BandUI2.png&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-width&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Health and Health Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Health is the app you use to configure and manage your Band. It has a &amp;ldquo;windowsy&amp;rdquo; look and feel event on iOS (including messed up margins on some screens). It can import data from the iOS Health app, so it can show you number of steps that the iPhone records. But it cannot export the data back to iOS Health. This means that data like the data about your sleep can be accessed only from the Microsoft Health app and are not propagated to other iOS app that can import data from iOS Health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/BandDashboard1.png&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can connect the Microsoft Health app to the Microsoft Health Vault, which has a nice web dashboard. This dashboard is more detailed and more simple to use that the app in the phone. But you have to be ok with your data being exported to some Microsoft data center. If you choose to use the Health Vault you can compare your data to groups of other people. I do not know about any other platforms that allows you to do this. And it is always nice to compare your data to people of similar age, height and weight and see that you condition is not as bad as you may have thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/BandDashboard2.png&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apps and Web Tiles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are not many 3rd party iOS apps, except big fitness apps like Strava, that can use the Band, but this is not a surprise. Band apps are maybe the only platform where Windows Phone has an advantage. Also there are not so many Web Tiles available, except for a couple of sports tiles made by the Bing team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided to write &lt;a href=&#34;mshealth-webtile://?action=download-manifest&amp;amp;url=https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/73642/kinoklub.webtile&#34;&gt;my own tile, showing the schedule of three Czech cinemas&lt;/a&gt;. The documentation for the Web Tiles is short and concise, the samples are ok, but there is no way to test your tiles other than deploying them to the real device. No data validity checker, no emulator and no good error messages. If you make a mistake, any mistake, be it an icon with wrong dimensions or invalid JSON manifest, the Microsoft Health app just gives you a generic error when trying to deploy the app to the Band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steps and Sleep tracking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Band counts your steps, distance traveled, floors climbed and checks your heart rate while at it. If you go for a run you can enable GPS and track your route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/BandSteps.png&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-width&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/BandGPS.png&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-width&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not have the Band on me while going to my Wing Chun practice. It would get destroyed. No similar devices are meant to be used when doing martial arts. It is a shame, I would be really interested to see my heart rate history doing the practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best feature for me was the already mentioned inactivity timer. I left it on the default setting, reminding me to wake up and take some steps after an hour of sitting at the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep tracking is the feature I was looking forward to the most. The Band track the time it takes you to fall asleep, the length and quality of your sleep (deep and light sleep cycles), the number of times you wake up and your heart rate. It can function as an alarm, waking you up in the morning by vibrating on your wrist. The alarm can be set to a specific time or you can use the smart alarm feature. The smart alarm monitors your sleep cycle and always wakes you up in a light sleep phase, up to 30 minutes before the time you set. For me it basically meant getting up 30 minutes earlier every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/BandSleep1.png&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-width&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/BandSleep2.png&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-width&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set the Band to show me notifications for incoming calls and SMS, nothing more. When a notification is invoked, the Band vibrates. The default medium intensity is not very intense, so I had to set it to high to be aware of it. When you receive a SMS, the band can &amp;ldquo;read&amp;rdquo; it to you by showing it on the screen quickly, so you do not have to scroll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not bother to set up notifications for other apps. But the Microsoft Health app also offered me notifications for Calendar, Facebook, Facebook Messenger, Twitter and a generic one called Notifications Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/BandUI1.png&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-width&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery usage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft Band 2 will stay charged for 2 days when not using the GPS. It is long as typical smartwatches, but if you are used to classical watches like I am, it is a very short time. It means another device to check status and charge. The Band will tell you to charge it long in advance. One day, I got a message to charge it at about 1 PM. By the time I got home after 6 PM the band battery indicator was red, but the Band was still working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Band charges really slow, compared to a phone or basically any other device. It wants you to think the process is faster, adding a percentage points every minute but then it gets stuck at 99% for about 40 minutes. You will always need at least two hours to charge it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annoyances&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the notifications and all the data are take from the phone and not really configurable. There is one thing that got me really annoyed when I discovered it. The iOS calendar app creates a calendar of peoples&amp;rsquo; birthdays. I have this calendar turned of in the iOS Calendar app and also in Sunrise, my calendar app of choice. But the Band does not respect this settings and also there is not configuration possible. So your calendar gets littered with birthdays and possible birthday notifications and there is nothing that you can do about it. Except disabling the calendar functionality on the Band. I know, I contacted Microsoft support (half an hour with probably an Indian guy, no solution, just my heart rate rising - Band told me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another annoyance is also related to notifications. If you turn on the Band, open a tile or go to some menu, turn off the Band, go on with your day and a notification approves, guess what happens? The Band vibrates, you turn it on and you are still in the last menu or tile and have no idea, what the notification was about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you switch your phone to a do not disturb mode, the Band completely ignores it and still notifies you about event, although your phone does not. You have to Switch the Band to a do not disturb mode separately every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one problem with the Band I had was the broken UV sensor. I could not immediately exchange the Band for a new one because I live in a country where the Bands is not sold and supported. It looks like &lt;a href=&#34;https://answers.microsoft.com/en-us/band/forum/msband-band_hardware/microsoft-band-uv-sensor-does-not-seem-to-work/97a7c92c-f135-48cd-8945-3781434d309c&#34;&gt;broken UV sensor is a common problem on both Band and Band 2&lt;/a&gt;. If you can buy it in a Microsoft Store (I was not), try if the UV sensor works, it may not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I called my local Microsoft technical support and the operator did not even know what Microsoft Band 2 was! After a while, maybe binging the name, she told me to get lost because they do not support it. Nice customer service as always, Microsoft Czech Republic. So I tried the UK support web page. I tried for three days and I always got the same response, telling me that they are busy chatting with someone else and that I can give them a UK phone number and they will call me back. Of course I do nod have a UK phone number. My next step will be contacting the US support after  see how that goes &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft Band 2 is a great health device. If you expectation are similar than mine than by all means get one. If you live in the US, go buy it to a Microsoft Store and test if everything works as supposed to. It may not. If you live outside the US, be aware that you may be on your own when something goes wrong. If you want a smartwatch or a device to keep track of notification, the Band is not for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I finally manage to chat with the UK support. I got a UPS label and sent the Band to Germany for repairs. After 6 work days I got a new Band.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobilize.net: Converting Windows Phone 8 apps to UWP? Not really</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/mobilize-net-converting-windows-phone-apps-to-uwp</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 09:29:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/mobilize-net-converting-windows-phone-apps-to-uwp</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Microsoft announced the Windows 10 developer platform, they also announced bridges to make porting apps from Android, iOS and Web easier. Those bridges are now either dead (Android) or unusable (iOS) but there is another tool that can be considered a bridge left. It is called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobilize.net/download-silverlight-bridge&#34;&gt;Mobilize.net Silverlight&lt;/a&gt; Bridge and it is not from Microsoft. It promises converting existing Windows Phone 8 (Silverlight apps) to the Universal Windows Platform. Considering the majority of apps in the Windows Phone Store are Windows Phone 8 apps and the fact that Android and iOS developers do not really care about Windows, Mobilize.net seem to be the most useful of the bridges, because there is no easy porting apps from Windows Phone 8 to UWP, just rewriting. So I tried it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/Windows10-Devices.png?t=1449725816496&amp;amp;width=425&amp;amp;height=210&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobilize.net is currently in technical preview. After you download and install it, it integrates into Visual Studio 2015 and there is a new context menu for Windows Phone 8 project, allowing you to convert them to UWP apps. If you use it, you get a dialog windows and a conversion process that will fail most of the times with a strange error. At least for me it did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got in touch with their support and I found out the reason for the conversion always failing. They do not support C# 6 all and mine, and probably all yours, project use C# 6. If you look at the error logs a bit closer, you will see error messages about failed tokenization. This is really strange, it looks like they are parsing the source code as text, instead of just using Roslyn. I do not get why, but they probably have a reason for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go through all the trouble and remove all the C# 6 features from your project, the conversion will succeed. You will get a UWP project, that will most likely not compile. There are two main reasons for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobilize.net changes your XAML to fix namespaces and replace controls that changed since Windows Phone 8, but it does not fix XAML features that were not available in UWP. And there are quite a few of them, from StringFormat in bindings to OpacityMask on images. You will have to fix your XAML manually and while you are at this, you will also have to rewrite your XAML to accommodate for the fact that there is not just one fixed resolution like it was in Windows Phone 8. Your XAML has to be responsive now. Mobilize.net did not really help here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seconds problem are third party libraries. There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MobilizeNet/UWPConversionMappings&#34;&gt;some mappings available for popular third party libraries&lt;/a&gt;. This mapping do two things. First they make sure the UWP project uses the correct Nuget packages and then they map namespaces, both in XAML and C#, that changed when the third party library transitioned from Windows Phone 8 to UWP. Chances are that there are no UWP versions of some or even the majority of the third party libraries you use. Probably because the functionality is nor longer available all the API has completely changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out to the Mobilize.net support asking about these two things, but I never got an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, if your app is not trivial, you use C# 6, third party libraries and all the available XAML features, your experience will not be very good. If you app is well written (MVVM, abstractions) your are better with creating a new UWP project, pasting your code and rewriting your XAML. If your app is more trivial, Mobilize.net will probably work well for you. But in this case, rewriting your app to UWP without it would be probably takes the same amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting gestures over WebView on Windows Phone</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/detecting-gestures-over-webview-on-windows-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 09:29:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/detecting-gestures-over-webview-on-windows-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you develop Windows Phone apps, you surely had to use the WebView component at least once. Any you must have realized, that it kind of sucks. One of the problems is that it swallows all the gestures and manipulation events. This means you cannot put it into a Pivot, you cannot detect swipe left or right events to navigate to next or previous article .. or can you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent project, I had to implement exactly the mentioned functionality, swiping between articles displayed in a WebView. I did some research and I could not find any solution. So I had to get creative and I find a way involving JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea was simple. If you cannot recognize the swipe event over the WebView in your C#/XAML, why not try to recognize them in the WebView? I did some research and found a JavaScript library that works on Windows Phone. The library is &lt;a href=&#34;https://hammerjs.github.io/&#34;&gt;Hammer&lt;/a&gt; and it recognizes all the basic gestures, including swiping left and right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you include Hammer into your HTML, then you set it up to listen over an HTML element and lastly you subscribe to events you are interested in. The only reasonable action you can execute is notify the WebView using the &lt;code&gt;window.external.notify&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/f7c559775ef3e57906ed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The C#/XAML part of the solution consists just of handling the WebView&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;ScriptNotify&lt;/code&gt; event and implementing your action according to the value you receive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sad state of DVLUP (MS Tech Rewards)</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/the-sad-state-of-dvlup-ms-tech-rewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 12:41:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/the-sad-state-of-dvlup-ms-tech-rewards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a Windows Phone developer you must know DVLUP. It was a program for developers developed by Nokia. The idea was simple. Do Windows Phone development related challenges, make your apps better thanks to them, get points, exchange points for rewards. Sounds good, does it not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting, but location dependent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with DVLUP was that it was location dependent. It opened in my countries maybe two years after US and developers from other &amp;ldquo;more important&amp;rdquo; countries could participate. The challenges were also location dependent, showing me only a small subset in my country. But they were interesting. They made me implement some new stuff into my apps that I would not do otherwise. And I got points for doing them. When I wanted to exchange the points for some rewards, there were not that many available in my country. No phones or other hardware like in the US. A Steam gift card was the only useful think that I could get. But I did not mind, I liked doing the challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then Microsoft bought Nokia and slowly DVLUP turned into MS Tech Rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pushing Universal Apps too hard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, all the challenges changed to challenges for Windows 10 apps only. They do not seem to care that most of the Windows Phone apps in the Store or in the works are for 8 or 8.1. Rewriting 8 and 8.1 apps that work well on 10 is simply not feasible. To me its seems like pushing Universal Apps too hard, ignoring the developers that invested in the Windows Phone platform in the beginning and created apps before Universal Apps were a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, they will tell you that making a 8 or 8.1 app into a 10 app is not rewriting, but porting. They can even argue with you about this on Twitter. But you know better. Maybe you are fed up of rewriting, you did it from 7 to 8 and from 8.1 ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More stupid challenges, new rules, still not good rewards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that making all the challenges for Windows 10 apps only made the developer participate a lot less. Otherwise they would not come with the new stupid rules. One of the rules is that you have to participate challenges with a given period, otherwise your earned points (the points you cannot spend on anything useful) would expire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the DVLUP challenges were making you to implement unique Windows Phone features to your apps. It sometimes looked a bit forceful, but generally it was ok. Now that Windows 10 Mobile lost all of the Windows Phone unique features, the challenges are getting really stupid sometimes. Just take a look at a challenge called &lt;a href=&#34;https://rewards.msdn.microsoft.com/Challenge/1c0a75a4-e198-4d52-9be2-5f9d2279848c&#34;&gt;Give Your Windows 10 App a Festive Holiday Glow&lt;/a&gt;. Reminds me of times when people put JavaScript snow on their websites in Winter. About 15 years ago. And it looks like I am not the only one who thinks it is really stupid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Oh god no &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MSTechRewards&#34;&gt;@MSTechRewards&lt;/a&gt; please don&amp;#39;t make people do shitty stuff like this &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Pmm4ofyT5c&#34;&gt;https://t.co/Pmm4ofyT5c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Morten Nielsen (@dotMorten) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dotMorten/status/667743323633774592&#34;&gt;November 20, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, DVLUP is dead, I really do not want to rewrite my apps for Windows 10 and add Christmas theming to them. It makes me sad it ended this way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going static: From Wordpress to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/going-static-from-wordpress-to-hugo</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 13:13:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/going-static-from-wordpress-to-hugo</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2015/11/modern-static-website-generators-next-big-thing/?utm_content=buffer882bd&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34;&gt;static site generation is the next big think&lt;/a&gt;. When I created this blog a few years ago I choose Wordpress, because it seemed like a good choice. Now I have grown tired with updating plugins, exchanging broken plugins for alternative ones and so one. So I decided to try to go the static site generation route to make the blog easier to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll? Octopress? FsBlog? Hugo!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.staticgen.com/&#34;&gt;quite a few static site generators&lt;/a&gt; out there, so choosing the right one is quite a challenge. &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org/&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; seemed like the obvious choice. Jekyll requires Ruby, which is ok even on Windows, but Octopress had a few dependencies that I did not manage to get working on Windows. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fsprojects/FsBlog&#34;&gt;FsBlog&lt;/a&gt; seemed interesting, especially for me being a F# enthusiast, but frankly it is not yet very usable. So I choose Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is a static site generator written in Go. That means no dependencies, just one binary you download and use. On Windows, you can even &lt;a href=&#34;https://chocolatey.org/packages/hugo&#34;&gt;get it using Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt;. It has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/quickstart/&#34;&gt;nice tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, a lively community and a few ready made themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting the content from Wordpress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are coming to Hugo from Wordpress, there is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SchumacherFM/wordpress-to-hugo-exporter&#34;&gt;plugin to export all the content for you&lt;/a&gt;. The only problem with the plugin is that it completely ignores Gists you reference in your posts. So after you export your posts, you have to manually edit one by one and add the Gists. Some Hugo themes offer you ready made shortcodes for embedding Gists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosting on Github Pages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I wanted to try after switching to a static website was hosting it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;, because the Git deployment story is more comfortable than copying or syncing the generated content over FTP to my hosting provider. Github Pages also offer kind of a CDN for your content. Setting it all up is not very complicated, there is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;tutorial in Hugo documentation that will walk you through the process&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are a few limitations when using with Github Pages. There are no redirects, so I could not redirect my RRS feed to the new one. A much bigger problem is that there is no way to set caching time for static resources like CSS and JS files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling and disabling hardware devices with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/enabling-and-disabling-hardware-devices-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/enabling-and-disabling-hardware-devices-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a built-in fingerprint reader on my Thinkpad notebook that I use for loging in almost exclusively. I say almost because since I upgraded to Windows 10 it sometimes just stops working when the computer wakes up from sleep. I found out that to make it work again I have to go to the Device Manager, find it, disable it and enabled it back again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I was looking for a way to automate this, because I do not think that this issue will be fixed any time soon by Microsoft or Lenovo. I found out there is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/Device-Management-7fad2388&#34;&gt;PowerShell cmdlet that expose device enumeration and management APIs&lt;/a&gt;. Using this cmdlet I wrote a simple PowerShell script to the the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has to be run with administrator privileges to work. Maybe I will go one step further and make this script run each time the notebook wakes up, just to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/3bea04333c0b47156c68.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio extensions to make your life easier</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/visual-studio-extensions-to-make-your-life-easier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/visual-studio-extensions-to-make-your-life-easier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post is inspired by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hmemcpy.com/2015/10/7-open-source-visual-studio-extensions-to-make-your-life-easier/&#34;&gt;7 open-source Visual Studio Extensions to make your life easier&lt;/a&gt; article. In the article Igal Tabachnik showed his favorite Visual Studio extensions, that were quite interesting. I also use a few Visual Studio extensions that make my life easier, so I decided to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/e792686d-542b-474a-8c55-630980e72c30&#34;&gt;Indent Guides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small and simple extension with just one task, displaying indent and page width guides in Visual Studio text editor windows. There are three styles of guides: solid, dotted and dashed, available in thin and thick varieties and customizable color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/guides.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/f4d9c2b5-d6d7-4543-a7a5-2d7ebabc2496&#34;&gt;VSColorOutput&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VSColorOutput can change the color of a line emitted to the output window based on specified rules. The rules consist of regular expressions. Rules map to classifications which in turn map to colors. The default patterns will color build errors in red, warnings in yellow/gold and successful build messages in green. It also colors the output of debug messages when running an app, so you can easily sort exceptions and your custom debug messages containing certain words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/vscoloroutput.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/f3f23845-5b1e-4811-882f-60b7181fa6d6&#34;&gt;Rename Visual Studio Windows Title&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Visual Studio shows the name of the opened solution name in the title. This makes it easier to navigate among multiple instances of Visual Studio. You see the solution name next to the Visual Studio icon in the taskbar and also in the task manager, when you have to (and we all sometimes have to) kill the right Visual Studio because it stopped responding. You can use it with Git and show the branch or any other info. For more information about this extension, see a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.kulman.sk/quick-tip-showing-solution-branch-name-in-visual-studio-title/&#34;&gt;separate blog post I wrote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/trayalya.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/03448836-db42-46b3-a5c7-5fc5d36a8308&#34;&gt;AsyncFixer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AsyncFixer helps developers in finding and correcting 3 common async/await misuses. AsyncFixer was tested with hundreds of C# apps and successfully handles many corner cases. AsyncFixer will work just in the IDE and work as an analyzer on every project you open in Visual Studio. It can also operate in batch mode to correct all misuses in the document, project, or solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/asyncfixer-1.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenovo, why do you screw Thinkpads with every update?</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/lenovo-why-do-you-screw-thinkpads-with-every-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/lenovo-why-do-you-screw-thinkpads-with-every-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a Lenovo Thinpad T440s that I got about a year ago after a great experience with a company issued Lenovo Thinkpad T420 I used for about two and half years before that. I use it daily for on-site work, not so much at home, where I have a desktop computer. The T440s is thinner and lighter than T420, but otherwise everything is just worse. You cannot change RAM or disk so easily as on the T420, the keyboard and trackpoint are worse (the trackpoint does not have physical buttons like on the T420 but &lt;a href=&#34;http://camerongray.me/2015/02/fitting-physical-trackpoint-buttons-to-a-lenovo-thinkpad-t440s/&#34;&gt;I had it replaced for one that does&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why did I get the T440s? Because it seemed like a wise choice at the time, compared to the competition. It has a trackpoint, fingerprint reader, a keyboard with all the keys in the right place and it is, after all, a Thinkpad, a sturdy and reliable work machine build from good materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not really. As every Thinkpad fan can tell you, the quality of Thinkpads is declining (even when not counting the plastic Thinkpad Edge computers that are not &amp;#8220;real&amp;#8221; Thinkpads). It seems like Lenovo simply does not care, making the hardware worse and software even more so. Gone are the superb ThinkVantage tools, only the Thinkpad update utility remained. And it often install software and drivers that can screw up your computer. It happened to many times, this is the latest incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security BIOS update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest problem is with a BIOS update. Lenovo releases BIOS 2.35 for my T440s, fixing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.lenovo.com/us/en/product_security/smm_attack&#34;&gt;SMM &amp;#8220;Incursion&amp;#8221; Attack&lt;/a&gt;. The BIOS update as pushed to me as critical using the Thinkpad update tools and fixing security problems is always a good thing. So I installed it. And problems started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I put the computer to sleep and it went from sleep to hibernation after 180 minutes (default settings), the computer started to beep madly and hung on a black screen. Not really a good sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured it must be because of the BIOS update, so I went to the Lenovo website to download the previous BIOS update. I downloaded BIOS 2.34 and could not installed it because of I strange error. Then I noticed this note in the BIOS 2.35 changelog: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;If the UEFI BIOS has been updated to version 2.35 or higher, it is no longer able to roll back to the version before 2.35 for security improvement.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt;. So my computer got screwed. I had a problematic BIOS and could not downgrade. Great work Lenovo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insecure workaround&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some research and &lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.lenovo.com/t5/ThinkPad-T400-T500-and-newer-T/T440s-beeps-while-putting-in-sleep-mode-and-a-blank-screen/m-p/2191866&#34;&gt;found out that the problem is related to the TPM chip&lt;/a&gt;. I use the TPM chip with BitLocker in Windows 10, so It looked like it maybe be the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I turned off BitLocker, waited for my disk do get decrypted and disabled the TPM in BIOS. I put the computer to sleep, waited for it to go to hibernation, and nothing happened. No beeps, no problems, the computer woke normally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have a BIOS (that I cannot get rid of) with the security fix for an obscure issue but my disk is not encrypted and when I loose my computer or it gets stolen, anyone can read my data. Again, great work Lenovo. Time to install TrueCrypt I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: it took two month for Lenovo to acknowledge the problem and release a fix.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlighting letters in TextBlock in Windows Phone 8.1 and Windows 8.1</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/highlighting-letters-in-textblock-in-windows-phone-8-1-and-windows-8-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/highlighting-letters-in-textblock-in-windows-phone-8-1-and-windows-8-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my current project I had to implement an interesting feature for both Windows Phone 8.1 and Windows 8.1 project of the Universal app. The idea is simply. The users want to search for a movie. They enter a search term into a TextBox and a list of results is shown. The results should have the search term highlighted in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/highlighting.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard TextBlock used to display the movie titles does not support any kind of letter highlighting, so I had to write a custom one. I created a custom UserControl. The UserControl contains a few dependency properties Text, HighlightedText, HighlightBrush and a TextBlock. When Text or HighlightedText change, the Text is then split into multiple Runs that are added to the TextBlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/87b051f2f3a54bf895f0.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole working custom control is available at Github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/igorkulman/Kulman.WPA81.HighlightTextBox&#34;&gt;https://github.com/igorkulman/Kulman.WPA81.HighlightTextBox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange combination of HTTPS and Windows Phone 8.1 that can make your app and phone freeze</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/strange-combination-of-https-and-windows-phone-8-1-that-can-make-your-app-and-phone-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/strange-combination-of-https-and-windows-phone-8-1-that-can-make-your-app-and-phone-freeze/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I came upon a really bizarre problem that you may also find interesting. Lets start with a bit of context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tl;Dr&lt;/strong&gt;: There seems to be a bug in Windows phone 8.1 that can make your app and the phone freezes when displaying images over HTTPS from some servers. Skip to &lt;a href=&#34;#bug&#34;&gt;the end of this article&lt;/a&gt; to see a video and get the source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Windows Phone app&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is a Windows Phone 8 shopping app for the biggest Czech online retailer. The main screen of the app contains quite a bit of data, usually about ten carousel with about 10 products and the list of main categories, so about 10 more images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In worst case the main screen contains over 10 hundred images. It was quite a hassle to make it work well in the Windows Phone 8 SDK (no, rewriting a shopping about with about 70 screens to Windows Phone 8.1 is not feasible). But it work juts fine. Until last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, users started to report that the app freezes on the main screen, sometime making the whole phone freeze. This was really bad. Frozen app means not only angry customers but customer that do not buy stuff. So I started to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I thought there may be a problem in the app, although the app was last updated more than a month ago and the problem started only last week. Everything worked fine in the emulator, the problem was reproducible only on real devices. I tried showing only one carousel to make the app render much less data, did not help. I tried making the app show only one product in the only one carousel, still a problem. So it looked like the images were the problem. I tried replacing all the real image urls with random images from &lt;a href=&#34;http://lorempixel.com&#34;&gt;lorempixel.com&lt;/a&gt; and the app worked just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I determined that the source of the problems are the images on the server. Talking with the server customer&amp;#8217;s people I found out that the images on the server were exchanged for bigger one because of the iPhones. But it did not make sense. I tried using much bigger random images and the app worked fine. I tried downloading the images and using them locally, the app worked fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&#34;bug&#34;&gt;Windows Phone 8.1 bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I found out that the app worked the whole time on phones with Windows 10, only phones with Windows Phone 8.1 were affected. Android and iOS apps that the customer has also never experienced this problem. This make me thing that there is some kind of bug in Windows Phone 8.1 that causes this behavior, because the app does not do any image processing, it only uses an Image control and sets is Source url.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a sample app to reproduce the problem: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/igorkulman/WindowsPhoneHttpsImageBug&#34;&gt;https://github.com/igorkulman/WindowsPhoneHttpsImageBug&lt;/a&gt;. The solution contains a Windows Phone 8 project and a Windows Phone 8.1. Both apps suffer from the sample problem, but the problem is worse in the Silverlight app. This also makes me think that this is a Windows Phone 8.1 bug, independent on the Windows Phone SDK version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a video using the sample app showing the problem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/138747871&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsofts Outlook on Android and iOS</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/microsofts-outlook-on-android-and-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/microsofts-outlook-on-android-and-ios/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To those who dont know, Microsoft launched several months ago Outlook for Android and iOS phones and tablets. Microsofts new brand of Outlook have replace the failing Outlook-branded apps that are only available to the current subscribers of Office 365. The upheaval comes after Microsoft acquired San Francisco-based company, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.acompli.com/&#34;&gt;Acompli.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/Outlook-Best-New-Apps.png&#34; class=&#34;pure-img-width&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acompli is an advanced email application that empowers professionals to do more with emails, full calendaring, easy file sharing and log all the important people in one email format. The format supports Microsofts Office 365, Gmail and Google Apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsofts plan is for both the Accompli and the new Outlook app to replace the rather dated Outlook-branded apps. The newfangled Outlook app is primarily based on the technology from the Acompli app that the company acquired for $200 million. Microsoft stated that it was a major factor in buying the app, as its staff could then make up the core group of engineers needed to drive the new Outlook app forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its no surprise that Microsoft is shifting its focus from PC-installed base as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekwire.com/2014/flurry-report-mobile-phones-162-minutes/&#34;&gt;GeekWire.com&lt;/a&gt; reports that a study showed Americans spend approximately 162 minutes a day on their phones browsing. And with Gaming Realms, the developer behind the entertainment medium &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pocketfruity.com/casino&#34;&gt;PocketFruity.com&lt;/a&gt;, claiming that the global smartphone use has now reached 17%, apps are seeing a spike regarding financial investments and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see how well the new Outlook app is received after a year or so. With the app retaining many of the features that its recent acquisition Acompli successfully exhibited, theres a possibility that the consumer base may just stay with the Acompli until Outlook perfects the new app further, and add features that will set it apart from other leading email applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems getting paid from the Windows Store, again</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/problems-getting-paid-from-the-windows-store-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/problems-getting-paid-from-the-windows-store-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I do not make much money on my Windows Phone apps (who does?), but when the payout time comes every couple of months, I expect the money to be delivered. Dealing with Microsoft, I should know better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failed payment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month I looked into the Dev Center and saw that my scheduled payment failed, telling me to contact the support. So I did. The result was one moth of exchanging email without a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dealing with support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft employee told me that I am in a small group of people with this problem. I do not know if I have such a bad look always be in a problematic supposedly small group, or that the group are not that small. He told me that Microsoft will retry the payment. The payment was supposedly retried on June 24th and succeeded. So they say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Great news, your June payout was returned due to an internal issue; however, the payout of 5264.17 CZK has been re-attempted and was successfully completed on June 24th. If you have not received the payout then please review this transaction with your bank. Please let me know if you have any further questions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never got the money. The employee asked me a few times if I got the money and then resigned, telling me that it is my problem and I should check with my bank. Of course I checked with my bank, they do not have the money. If they had, they would transfer it to my account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will it happen again?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the support is not helpful, I think I will never see this money and I can just hope the next payment in a couple of months will be successful. Will it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a look at my payout settings in the new Dev Center and it is a mess&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/payout.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;

&lt;p&gt;It previous pages is telling my that everything is ok and my data is valid, but is it? Those four radios do not give me the confidence to believe it. Especially seeing my old account (x3168) that was there in the Windows Store and I deleted it. I used to get the payment to the x0026 account that was in my Windows Phone Store account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny thing about this form, I never found out how to delete this old account. If you select it, you can only edit it, no way to delete it. If I select the correct account and click save, nothing changes, the radios all remain unselected. I do now know it is a bug or another great Microsoft UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I guess maybe the next payment will also get lost somewhere ..&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip: Showing solution branch name in Visual Studio title</title>
      <link>https://blog.kulman.sk/quick-tip-showing-solution-branch-name-in-visual-studio-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kulman.sk/quick-tip-showing-solution-branch-name-in-visual-studio-title/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By default, Visual Studio shows the name of the opened solution name in the title. This makes it easier to navigate among multiple instances of Visual Studio. You see the solution name next to the Visual Studio icon in the taskbar and also in the task manager, when you have to (and we all sometimes have to) kill the right Visual Studio because it stopped responding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work with Git, switching branches frequently, especially working on features and bug fixes. In this situation, it would be nice if Visual Studio showed not only the solution name but also the current branch in its title. No problem, there is an extension for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extension is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/f3f23845-5b1e-4811-882f-60b7181fa6d6&#34;&gt;Rename Visual Studio Window&lt;/a&gt; and it works with Visual Studio 2015, 2013, 2012, 2010. This extension supports Git, so you can easily add the branch name to the title with a config like mine using [gitBranchName].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/rename.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your taskbar will then look like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.kulman.sk/images/trayalya.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>