<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rants on Coding Journal</title>
    <link>http://blog.kulman.sk/categories/rants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rants on Coding Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 12:41:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.kulman.sk/categories/rants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The sad state of DVLUP (MS Tech Rewards)</title>
      <link>http://blog.kulman.sk/the-sad-state-of-dvlup-ms-tech-rewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 12:41:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.kulman.sk/the-sad-state-of-dvlup-ms-tech-rewards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a Windows Phone developer you must know DVLUP. It was a program for developers developed by Nokia. The idea was simple. Do Windows Phone development related challenges, make your apps better thanks to them, get points, exchange points for rewards. Sounds good, does it not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting, but location dependent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with DVLUP was that it was location dependent. It opened in my countries maybe two years after US and developers from other &amp;ldquo;more important&amp;rdquo; countries could participate. The challenges were also location dependent, showing me only a small subset in my country. But they were interesting. They made me implement some new stuff into my apps that I would not do otherwise. And I got points for doing them. When I wanted to exchange the points for some rewards, there were not that many available in my country. No phones or other hardware like in the US. A Steam gift card was the only useful think that I could get. But I did not mind, I liked doing the challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then Microsoft bought Nokia and slowly DVLUP turned into MS Tech Rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pushing Universal Apps too hard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, all the challenges changed to challenges for Windows 10 apps only. They do not seem to care that most of the Windows Phone apps in the Store or in the works are for 8 or 8.1. Rewriting 8 and 8.1 apps that work well on 10 is simply not feasible. To me its seems like pushing Universal Apps too hard, ignoring the developers that invested in the Windows Phone platform in the beginning and created apps before Universal Apps were a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, they will tell you that making a 8 or 8.1 app into a 10 app is not rewriting, but porting. They can even argue with you about this on Twitter. But you know better. Maybe you are fed up of rewriting, you did it from 7 to 8 and from 8.1 ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More stupid challenges, new rules, still not good rewards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that making all the challenges for Windows 10 apps only made the developer participate a lot less. Otherwise they would not come with the new stupid rules. One of the rules is that you have to participate challenges with a given period, otherwise your earned points (the points you cannot spend on anything useful) would expire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the DVLUP challenges were making you to implement unique Windows Phone features to your apps. It sometimes looked a bit forceful, but generally it was ok. Now that Windows 10 Mobile lost all of the Windows Phone unique features, the challenges are getting really stupid sometimes. Just take a look at a challenge called &lt;a href=&#34;https://rewards.msdn.microsoft.com/Challenge/1c0a75a4-e198-4d52-9be2-5f9d2279848c&#34;&gt;Give Your Windows 10 App a Festive Holiday Glow&lt;/a&gt;. Reminds me of times when people put JavaScript snow on their websites in Winter. About 15 years ago. And it looks like I am not the only one who thinks it is really stupid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Oh god no &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MSTechRewards&#34;&gt;@MSTechRewards&lt;/a&gt; please don&amp;#39;t make people do shitty stuff like this &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Pmm4ofyT5c&#34;&gt;https://t.co/Pmm4ofyT5c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Morten Nielsen (@dotMorten) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dotMorten/status/667743323633774592&#34;&gt;November 20, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, DVLUP is dead, I really do not want to rewrite my apps for Windows 10 and add Christmas theming to them. It makes me sad it ended this way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenovo, why do you screw Thinkpads with every update?</title>
      <link>http://blog.kulman.sk/lenovo-why-do-you-screw-thinkpads-with-every-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.kulman.sk/lenovo-why-do-you-screw-thinkpads-with-every-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a Lenovo Thinpad T440s that I got about a year ago after a great experience with a company issued Lenovo Thinkpad T420 I used for about two and half years before that. I use it daily for on-site work, not so much at home, where I have a desktop computer. The T440s is thinner and lighter than T420, but otherwise everything is just worse. You cannot change RAM or disk so easily as on the T420, the keyboard and trackpoint are worse (the trackpoint does not have physical buttons like on the T420 but &lt;a href=&#34;http://camerongray.me/2015/02/fitting-physical-trackpoint-buttons-to-a-lenovo-thinkpad-t440s/&#34;&gt;I had it replaced for one that does&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why did I get the T440s? Because it seemed like a wise choice at the time, compared to the competition. It has a trackpoint, fingerprint reader, a keyboard with all the keys in the right place and it is, after all, a Thinkpad, a sturdy and reliable work machine build from good materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not really. As every Thinkpad fan can tell you, the quality of Thinkpads is declining (even when not counting the plastic Thinkpad Edge computers that are not &amp;#8220;real&amp;#8221; Thinkpads). It seems like Lenovo simply does not care, making the hardware worse and software even more so. Gone are the superb ThinkVantage tools, only the Thinkpad update utility remained. And it often install software and drivers that can screw up your computer. It happened to many times, this is the latest incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security BIOS update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest problem is with a BIOS update. Lenovo releases BIOS 2.35 for my T440s, fixing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.lenovo.com/us/en/product_security/smm_attack&#34;&gt;SMM &amp;#8220;Incursion&amp;#8221; Attack&lt;/a&gt;. The BIOS update as pushed to me as critical using the Thinkpad update tools and fixing security problems is always a good thing. So I installed it. And problems started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I put the computer to sleep and it went from sleep to hibernation after 180 minutes (default settings), the computer started to beep madly and hung on a black screen. Not really a good sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured it must be because of the BIOS update, so I went to the Lenovo website to download the previous BIOS update. I downloaded BIOS 2.34 and could not installed it because of I strange error. Then I noticed this note in the BIOS 2.35 changelog: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;If the UEFI BIOS has been updated to version 2.35 or higher, it is no longer able to roll back to the version before 2.35 for security improvement.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt;. So my computer got screwed. I had a problematic BIOS and could not downgrade. Great work Lenovo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insecure workaround&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some research and [found out that the problem is related to the TPM chip][3]. I use the TPM chip with BitLocker in Windows 10, so It looked like it maybe be the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I turned off BitLocker, waited for my disk do get decrypted and disabled the TPM in BIOS. I put the computer to sleep, waited for it to go to hibernation, and nothing happened. No beeps, no problems, the computer woke normally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have a BIOS (that I cannot get rid of) with the security fix for an obscure issue but my disk is not encrypted and when I loose my computer or it gets stolen, anyone can read my data. Again, great work Lenovo. Time to install TrueCrypt I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.lenovo.com/t5/ThinkPad-T400-T500-and-newer-T/T440s-beeps-while-putting-in-sleep-mode-and-a-blank-screen/m-p/2191866&#34;&gt;https://forums.lenovo.com/t5/ThinkPad-T400-T500-and-newer-T/T440s-beeps-while-putting-in-sleep-mode-and-a-blank-screen/m-p/2191866&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>